Guide to the Congo (Brazzaville) Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Congo (Brazzaville) collection
1940-1995
1952-1986
MS 1511
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
(4 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to Congo (Brazzaville) and its political conditions. Also included are photographs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection (MS 605); Pamphlet Collection (MS 1351); African Postcard Collection (MS 1575). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically, with photographs last. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to Congo (Brazzaville) and its political conditions. Also included are photographs.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Congo (Brazzaville) -- Description and travel; Congo (Brazzaville) -- Politics and government
- Inventory
  - General information pamphlets; brochures; booklets, 1952-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Political organizations: bulletins; journals; newsletters; releases, 1978-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional Material, Accession 1998-M-053
  - "Mayansa pour la Démocratie", 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Réhabiliter le Kikongo," "L'Union Fédérale du Kikongo" [Bundu Dia Kongo (B. D. K.)], [1995?] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Bulletin d'Information" [ComitéCentral du Parti Congolais du Travail], 1981, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ces Charmants Diables Noirs, by Joseph Gabio [booklet on soccer], 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs [four scenes of Brazzaville; French government information photographs], [194-] (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Additional Material, Accession 2005-M-115
  - Centre Congolais du Commerce Extérieur, "Horizon 1978/80", 1977 June (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Comité Regional du Parti/Pool, "Action Tropicale," no. 1, [1986] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Confédération Syndicale Congolaise (CSC), "Voix de la Classe Ouvrière" (VOCO), Spéciale 5e Congrès, 1978 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional Material, 1973-1988; Accession 2010-M-102
  Arrangement
  The material is arranged as received.
  - L' éducateur Congolais et la Réforme, 1982 November (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ecole du Peuple, revue Mensuelle, 1977 November (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jeunesse et Révolution, 1982 February (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Flash, 1988 January
  - Brazzaville Decouvertes, pamphlet, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Telema, revue culturelle trimestrielle, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Licho, information bulletin of the University of Lubumbashi: Shaba, Zaire, 1982, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)